# J.D. Fillmore

jd@jdfill.me | (289) 213 - 3368 | https://jdfill.me | https://github.com/jd-fillmore

## **CAREER PROFILE**

Front-end developer with 7 years experience in developing functional, accessible websites and web applications for in-house corporations and clients. Experienced in leading projects from concept to launch as well as mentoring junior front-end developers.

Experienced in React, React Hooks, TypeScript, Styled Components, JavaScript (ES5/6), JavaScript Front-End Frameworks, Functional Programming, Storybook, GraphQL, REST APIs (JSON, Fetch API, Axios), GatsbyJS, NextJS, JAMStack, Content Management Systems, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Flexbox, Bootstrap, Netlify, Git, Version Control, Testing / Debugging, Responsive / Mobile Design, Adobe XD, Adobe Photoshop, Sketch, InVision, SEO, WCAG / AODA AA Accessibility, Agile

#### CAREER HIGHLIGHTS

- Development efforts directly generated over \$4,000,000 in revenue over one month during the height of the COVID-19 pandemic for Battlefield Equipment Rentals
- Contributed to a web application on the front-end which was used by 14,000,000 people worldwide
- Catered to persons with disabilities through having programmed accessible websites and web applications
- Have worked alongside industry giants such as Tim Hortons and PC Financial

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**Front-End Developer, Team Lead** | Battlefield Equipment Rentals (Toromont Cat) | Remote Dec. 2019 - Present Administer and integrate features to React & TypeScript web application, lead all web projects from inception to launch.

- Code & design national product landing pages, achieving \$3,000,000 in revenue in May 2020 during the COVID-19 pandemic
- Maintain and implement features to a React, JavaScript & TypeScript web application, generating over \$1,000,000 of revenue within the first month
- Implement dynamic product filtering and image categorization to web application increasing user experience

# Front-End Developer (Contract) | VelocityEHS | Oakville, ON

June 2019 - Dec. 2019

Developed UI features to the front-end of React web application,, team lead for accessibility, mentored junior developers.

- Added UI features to new React v6 web app, increasing accessibility and user experience for persons with disabilities by 100%
- AODA accessibility team lead, mentored and educated internal team (2 UX designers / 2 frontend developers)
- Constructed Storybook reusable code component library, decreased development time by over 50%
- Conducted and participated in code reviews, reduced errors by 50%

## Front-End Developer, UI / UX Designer, Project Manager | Freelance Consultant | Remote

April 2013 - Present

Design & build modern websites using React (GatsbyJS), manage clients, build web applications for learning purposes.

- 60% increase in all clients overall local SEO rankings due to accessibility, speed, user experience & performance
- Notable side clients <u>Cass-A-Bella Construction</u>, <u>KD Flowers</u>, <u>MC Aesthetics</u> React / Gatsby-based websites
- Featured pet projects Maple Leafs Stats, Movie Database React-based web apps with API integration

# Front-End Developer | Thrillworks | Burlington, ON

April 2018 - June 2019

Constructed modern websites using React (GatsbyJS) and worked with clients such as Tim Hortons and PC Financial.

- Crafted reusable code component library, decreasing development time by over 60%
- One of four leading members of the AODA AA Accessibility Board, educated internal staff on accessibility

Designed and created content management websites as well as managed client projects from start to finish.

- 60% decrease in development time of websites due to component based libraries
- Created client designs increasing user engagement and experience by 120% compared to old websites
- Local SEO efforts leading to a 70% increase in local Google client rankings

Front-End Developer (Contract) | Elite Digital | Toronto, ON

March 2016 - Sept. 2016

Front-End Developer, UI / UX Designer | iOPW | Toronto, ON

Aug. 2014 - March 2016

**EDUCATION** 

Durham College, Oshawa, ON | Advanced Diploma in Multimedia Design

April 2010